Guide to 20th Century International Poster Collection, circa 1914-1950
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
20th Century International Poster Collection
circa 1914-1950
264 items
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Propaganda posters dating from the start of World War I, through World War II, and into the post-war period. The bulk of the items were produced in the United States or France, but there are also items from other European countries, as well as Canada.
Scope and Content Note
Propaganda posters dating from the start of World War I, through World War II, and into the post-war period. The bulk of the items were produced in the United States or France, but there are also items from other European countries, as well as Canada.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged physically by size, and intellectually by country and date.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Subjects:
World War, 1914-1918--Posters; Propaganda; War posters; World War, 1939-1945--Posters
Document Types:
Posters
VCL Categories:
Politics; War and War Crimes
Encoding Information
Encoded by Laura Streett, January 2015.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Some of the largest posters may have damage and need special handling.
Acquisition Information
The origin of most of the posters is unknown, but the eight USSR Posters were a gift of Ebenezer Hill in 1928.
Other Formats
There are low-quality images available to browse before the original posters will be pulled for research.
Container List
- SERIES I. United States, circa 1917-1950; (98 posters)
  - World War I, circa 1917-1918; (9 posters, 20" x 24" folders) (01.01.001 - 01.01.009)
  - World War I, circa 1917-1918; (38 posters, 24" x 36" folders) (01.01.010 - 01.01.047)
  - World War I, circa 1917-1918; (1 poster, oversize) (01.01.048)
  - World War I, circa 1917-1918; (23 posters, 36" x 48" folders) (01.01.049 - 01.01.071)
  - Between World War I and World War II, circa 1918-1939; (3 posters, 20" x 24" folders) (01.03.001 - 01.03.003)
  - World War II, circa 1939-1945; (2 posters, 20" x 24" folders) (01.02.001 - 01.02.002)
  - World War II, circa 1939-1945; (12 posters, 24" x 36" folders) (01.02.003 - 01.02.014)
  - World War II, circa 1939-1945; (4 posters, 36" x 48" folders) (01.02.015 - 01.02.018)
  - World War II, circa 1939-1945; (5 posters, 20" x 24" folders) (01.02.019 - 01.02.023)
  - Post-World War II, circa 1945-1950; (1 poster, 20" x 24" folder) (01.04.001)
  - Post-World War II, circa 1945-1950; (2 posters, 24" x 36" folders) (01.04.002 - 01.04.003)
- SERIES II. France, circa 1917-1945; (77 posters)
  - World War I, circa 1914-1918; (24 posters, 24" x 36" folders) (02.01.001 - 02.01.024)
  - World War I, circa 1914-1918; (7 posters, 20" x 24" folders) (02.01.025 - 02.01.031)
  - World War I, circa 1914-1918; (26 posters, 36" x 48" folders) (02.01.032 - 02.01.057)
  - World War I, circa 1914-1918; (1 poster, oversize) (02.01.058)
  - World War I, circa 1914-1918; (14 posters, 24" x 36" folders) (02.01.059 - 02.01.072)
  - Between World War I and World War II, circa 1918-1939; (3 posters, 36" x 48" folders) (02.02.001 - 02.02.003)
  - Between World War I and World War II, circa 1918-1939; (1 poster, 20" x 24" folders) (02.02.004)
  - World War II, circa 1939-1945; (1 poster, 20" x 24" folder) (02.03.001)
- SERIES III. United Kingdom, circa 1917-1945; (32 posters)
  - World War I, circa 1914-1918; (2 posters, 20" x 24" folders) (03.01.001 - 03.01.002)
  - World War I, circa 1914-1918; (4 posters, 24" x 36" folders) (03.01.003 - 03.01.006)
  - World War I, circa 1914-1918; (3 posters, 36" x 48" folders) (03.01.007 - 03.01.009)
  - Between World War I and World War II, circa 1918-1939; (18 posters, 24" x 36" folders) (03.03.001 - 03.03.018)
  - Between World War I and World War II, circa 1918-1939; (1 poster, 36" x 48" folder) (03.03.019)
  - World War II, circa 1939-1945; (2 posters, 20" x 24" folders) (03.02.001 - 03.02.002)
  - World War II, circa 1939-1945; (2 posters, 24" x 36" folders) (03.02.003 - 03.02.004)
- SERIES IV. Canada, circa 1939-1945; (2 posters)
  - World War II, circa 1939-1945; (2 posters, 24" x 36" folders) (04.01.001 - 04.01.002)
- SERIES V. Italy, circa 1914-1918; (1 poster)
  - World War I, circa 1914-1918; (1 poster, 36" x 48" folder) (05.01.001)
- SERIES VI. Poland, circa 1918-1939; (1 poster)
  - Between World War I and World War II, circa 1918-1939; (1 poster, 36" x 48" folder) (06.01.001)
- SERIES VII. Germany, circa 1914-1918; (7 posters)
  - World War I, circa 1914-1918; (5 posters, 20" x 24" folders) (07.01.001 - 07.01.005)
  - World War I, circa 1914-1918; (2 posters, 24" x 36" folders) (07.01.006 - 07.01.007)
- SERIES VIII. USSR, circa 1918-1939; (8 posters)
  - Between World War I and World War II, circa 1918-1939; (1 poster, 20" x 24" folders) (08.01.001)
  - Between World War I and World War II, circa 1918-1939; (1 poster, 24" x 36" folders) (08.01.002)
  - Between World War I and World War II, circa 1918-1939; (6 posters, 36" x 48" folders) (08.01.003 - 08.01.008)
- SERIES IX. Austria, circa 1939-1945; (36 posters)
  - World War II, circa 1939-1945; (12 posters, 20" x 24" folders) (09.01.001 - 09.01.012)
  - World War II, circa 1939-1945; (2 posters, 24" x 36" folders) (09.01.013 - 09.01.014)
  - World War II, circa 1939-1945; (10 posters, 36" x 48" folders) (09.01.015 - 09.01.024)
  - World War II, circa 1939-1945; (12 posters, oversize) (09.01.025 - 09.01.036)
- SERIES X. Belgium, circa 1914-1918; (1 poster)
  - World War I, circa 1914-1918; (1 poster, 36" x 48" folder) (10.01.001)